YWCA of the U.S.A. Records. Record Group 9. Photographs
Sophia Smith Collection
YWCA of the U.S.A. Records. Record Group 09. Photographs
circa 1890s-2001
Young Women's Christian Association of the U.S.A.
324_rg9
Sophia Smith Collection Smith College Northampton, MA
This Record Group includes photographic prints, negatives, slides and filmstrips documenting the work of the YWCA from the 1890s to the present. Forms part of the YWCA of the U.S.A. Records.
[Forms part of YWCA of the U.S.A. Records]
This Record Group is divided into three Series:
I. PRINTS AND NEGATIVES
II. SLIDES
III. FILMSTRIPS
The records are open to research according to the regulations of the Sophia Smith Collection without any additional restrictions.
Access to audiovisual materials may first require production of research copies.
Additional Formats
A copy of the microfilmed records of the YWCA of the U.S.A. Records is available to borrow from the William Allan Neilson Library at Smith College via Interlibrary Loan.
To request the microfilm from our library you will need to submit the following information to your library's Interlibrary Loan department:
Author: Young Women's Christian Association of the U.S.A. National Board
Title: Records, 1876-1970 [microform]
WorldCat Accession Number: OCLC 57415795
Notes: "Call # 689" and reel number(s) you want to borrow
Full descriptions and reel lists of the microfilm are available online.
The YWCA of the U.S.A. donated a portion of its records to the Sophia Smith Collection in 1964 and the remainder in 2002 and 2003.
Record Groups
The YWCA of the USA Records are arranged as follows:
YWCA of the U.S.A. Records (main record)
RECORD GROUP 1. GENERAL AND HISTORY
RECORD GROUP 2. PREDECESSOR ORGANIZATIONS AND NATIONAL BOARD
RECORD GROUP 3. NATIONAL ADMINISTRATIVE OFFICE
RECORD GROUP 4. NATIONAL CONVENTIONS AND CONFERENCES
RECORD GROUP 5. INTERNATIONAL WORK
RECORD GROUP 6. PROGRAM
RECORD GROUP 7. STUDENT WORK
RECORD GROUP 8. COMMUNITY ASSOCIATIONS
RECORD GROUP 9. PHOTOGRAPHS
RECORD GROUP 10. AUDIOVISUAL MATERIALS
Artifacts
The Microfilmed Records
The Oversized Materials
This Record group forms part of the YWCA of the U.S.A. Records
Series Descriptions
- SERIES I. PRINTS AND NEGATIVES
  Scope and Content
  This series is arranged in seven Subseries as follows:
  Subseries A. General and History
  Subseries B. National Board and National Administrative Office
  Subseries C. Conferences and Conventions
  Subseries D. International Work
  Subseries E. Program
  Subseries F. Student Work
  Subseries G. Community Associations
  The National YWCA photographic print collection consists of 45 linear feet of images, taken within the United States and abroad from the late 19th century through the first few years of the 21st. The majority of the photographs were taken by professional photographers for publicity use. A good portion of these document activities at Community YWCAs and were submitted to the National Association for use in its main serial The Association Monthly/Womans Press/YWCA Magazine.
  In addition to these publicity photographs, there are also a significant number of personal snapshots donated to the National Board Archives by retired staff members.
  The World War I-era section is particularly strong, with subjects ranging from U.S. Hostess Houses and Overseas Staff to the "Women at Work" war effort on both sides of the Atlantic. There is also a smaller collection of images documenting World War II, including scrapbook photos of Japanese Relocation Centers, United Community Defense Services trailer boom-towns and the history of the U.S.O.
  The bulk of the images taken within the United States are either from 1918 or from the late 1950s through early 1970s. Many of the Program section's broadest topics (Recreation, Students, Y-Teens) were taken in large part during the mid-1960s by staff photographer Carroll Aument, whose style is distinctive from that of other YWCA photographers.
  The majority of the images in all sections of the collection are in black and white. Color photographs taken in the 1970s-1990s are often lesser quality snapshots taken by YWCA staff members.
  The photographs are arranged to mirror the arrangement of the paper records in the following subseries:
  Subseries A. General and History includes Anniversaries, Exhibits, photographs of YWCA symbols and logos, such as the blue triangle and the YWCA purpose statement, World YWCA photographs, and miscellaneous and unidentified photographs. There is also a large file of photographs of individuals (arranged alphabetically) involved with the YWCA. These include local, regional, and national YWCA Board, Committee, and Council members, as well as speakers and celebrities at YWCA conferences, conventions, and other events.
  Subseries B. National Board and National Administrative Office includes photographs of the National Board and staff; nationally-owned buildings and properties; fund-raising committees and events; and photographs taken for use in YWCA publicity materials, such as posters and brochures.
  Subseries C. Conferences and Conventions consists of photographs taken at conferences, and National Conventions, and at preparatory and planning meetings.
  Subseries D. International Work includes a small amount of photographs of YWCA of the U.S.A. Foreign/International Division staff, programs, and conferences. The bulk of the Subseries is the Countries section which includes photographs of buildings, programs, staff, etc. taken at YWCAs in other countries. These are arranged alphabetically by country and then chronologically. Countries have been filed under their post-Independence names, for example, Rhodesia can be found under Zimbabwe and Ceylon under Sri Lanka. Refugees from Smyrna in 1922 have been filed with Turkey rather than Greece, while Palestinian refugees can be found in Jordan: Aqabat Jaber and Baqáa, Kalandia, Madaba, etc., folders.
  The Countries section is particularly strong in photographs from the following countries:
  Brazil 1950s and 1960s
  Chile 1960s
  China 1920s-1940s
  Ethiopia 1960s
  Germany 1945-1960s
  India 1910-1960s
  Japan 1920s-1960s
  Korea 1950s-1960s
  Lebanon 1920s-1960s
  Philippines 1920s-1970s
  Turkey 1920s-1960s
  Uganda 1950s-1960s
  Notable photo scrapbooks in this section cover program work in Buenos Aires in 1929, and Belgium, 1939-1940; a YWCA sponsored Neighborhood House in Berlin,1961-62; Kure, Japan, in 1948; YW sites in Russia at Archangel and Vladivostok in 1919; and two events in Turkey: the great fire of Smyrna in 1922 (refugees escaping to Greece) and a decade later the Cadde Bostan summer camp in 1932.
  The bulk of the countries photographs date from the 1960s, but a few of the country files (including China, India and Japan) have substantial photographs from the 1910s and 1920s. The majority of the photos within the international section are not dated.
  Subseries E. Program includes photographs of staff, committees, facilities, activities, and events related to public advocacy, personnel and training, constituent groups (including Immigrants, Interracial, Teen-age and Younger Girls, Young Adults), miscellaneous services and activities (such as residences, lunch rooms, child care/day care), subjects (camping and outdoor recreation, health, sports and fitness, recreation, music, pageantry and drama, religion) and War Work and Defense Services. Photographic documentation of World War I activities of women, both within the YWCA and among the general public.
  Subseries F. Student Work photographs include images of student staff, activities, conferences, councils and assemblies, programs and projects, and a few photographs of individual Student Associations.
  Subseries G. Community Associations photographs include images of general activities and groups; Community Association buildings and properties; and groups. The buildings and properties photographs are arranged by state. Groups photographs include classes, services, and events at Community Associations. Most of these images were subbmitted for publication in The Association Monthly/Womans Press/YWCA Magazine.
  Related Materials
  Because many of the photographs were published by the National Association, especially in its main serial, The Association Monthly/Womans Press/YWCA Magazine it is often possible to find related information about the photograph there. See especially RECORD GROUP 6. PROGRAM SERIES VI. PUBLICATIONS.
- SERIES II. SLIDES
  Scope and Contents
  Subseries A. General and History, slides of historical photographs; anniversary celebrations; unidentified individuals, groups, and events; logos, posters, and symbols; World YWCA (primarily World Council 1983, 1987)
  Subseries B. National Board and National Administrative Office Board meetings, buildings and properties, financial development events, scripted slide shows for publicity and financial development; miscellaneous historical slides made by the National Board Archives.
  Subseries C. Conferences and Conventions primarily slides taken at national Conventions early 1960s-94.
  Subseries D. International Work scripted slide shows on international themes, 1959-79; slides of YWCAs in other countries, 1963-87; slides taken by YWCA staff member Helen Mosier mostly in Africa and South America, late 1960s-early 1970s.
  Subseries E. Program primarily 1960s-70s range of constitutent groups and program subjects
  Subseries F. Student Work misc and Conferences and Council, late 1950s-78
  Subseries G. Community Associations modest number images of Community Associations buildings, activities, services, and events, mostly undated.
- SERIES III. FILMSTRIPS
  This Series contains scripts for 3 filmstrips for which no strip survives and one filmstrip late 1940s-mid 1950s.
- SERIES I. PRINTS AND NEGATIVES
  - Subseries A. General and History
    - Anniversaries
      - General, 1916-66 (Box 965, Folder 1)
      - World Centennial, 1955
        - General (Box 965, Folder 2)
        - Mary Bruce Sharon paintings (Box 965, Folder 3)
        - Radio City Music Hall ceremony, 24 Apr (Box 965, Folder 4)
        - Rockefeller Center plantings, Apr (Box 965, Folder 5)
        - Washington Luncheon, 11 Jan 1955 (Box 965, Folder 6)
      - Public Affairs Program 50th Anniversary, 1961 (Box 965, Folder 7)
      - YWCA of the USA 125th, 1983
        - General (Box 965, Folder 8)
        - Sondra Freckelton lithograph, 1983 (Box 965, Folder 9)
      - YWCA of the USA 135th, 1993-94
        - General, 1993 (Box 965, Folder 10)
        - New York City Gala, 27 Oct 1993 (Box 965, Folder 11)
        - Exhibit "Women First for 135 Years"
          - National Museum of Women in the Arts, 1993 (Box 965, Folder 12)
          - Washington D.C. and Los Angeles, 1993 (Box 965, Folder 13)
      - YWCA of the USA headquarters, 600 Lexington Avenue, New York City
        - 50th, 1962 (Box 965, Folder 14)
        - 70th, 1982 (Box 965, Folder 15)
      - United Service Organizations 30th Anniversary, 1971 (Box 965, Folder 16)
    - Art and Artifacts
      - General, 1895-1987 (Box 966, Folder 1)
      - Cartoons and Drawings, 1866-1985, n.d. (Box 966, Folder 2)
    - Exhibits, [see also Anniversaries]
      - General, 1952-91, n.d. (Box 966, Folder 3)
      - Annual Campaign, 1920 (Box 966, Folder 4)
      - Billboards, 1950-80, n.d. (Box 966, Folder 5)
      - Community Chest Drives, 1925?-50 (Box 966, Folder 6)
      - Member Associations, circa 1919-85, n.d. (Box 966, Folder 7)
      - National Board Exhibit Room, circa 1919-76, n.d. (Box 966, Folder 8)
      - National Industrial Progress Week, 1947 (Box 966, Folder 9)
      - National YWCA Week, 1949-78 (Box 966, Folder 10)
      - "Wherever She Is," circa 1960 (Box 966, Folder 11)
      - "Women Today Need...," 1962 (Box 966, Folder 12)
      - World War II era, circa 1945 (Box 966, Folder 13)
    - Panama-Pacific Exposition, San Francico, 1915
      - General, 1914-15 (Box 967, Folder 1)
      - Exteriors of YWCA building (Box 967, Folder 2)
      - Interiors and snapshots (Box 967, Folder 3)
      - Negatives [copy] (Box 967, Folder 4)
    - Postcards, circa 1920s-93 (Box 967, Folder 5)
    - Symbols
      - General, 1920s-80s (Box 967, Folder 6)
      - Banners, Flags and Quilts 1920-88 n.d. (Box 967, Folder 7)
      - Logo 1988-89 (Box 967, Folder 8)
      - Triangle 1924-1960s, n.d. (Box 967, Folder 9)
      - YWCA Purpose, 1949-67 (Box 967, Folder 10)
    - Uniforms, Dresses, and other clothing, 1892-1930, n.d. (Box 967, Folder 11)
    - World YWCA
      - General, 1907, n.d. (Box 967, Folder 12)
      - British and American YWCA, Paris, circa 1890s (Box 967, Folder 13)
      - Groups
        - 1898-1967 (Box 967, Folder 14-15)
        - 1970-80, n.d. (Box 968, Folder 1)
      - World Council Meetings
        - Vancouver, Canada, 1975 (Box 968, Folder 2)
        - Greece, 1979 (Box 968, Folder 3)
        - Singapore, 1983 (Box 968, Folder 4)
        - United States (Phoenix, Arizona), 1987 (Box 968, Folder 5-7)
        - Egypt, 1999 (Box 968, Folder 8)
      - World YWCA Pacific Area Regional Meeting, 1978 (Box 968, Folder 9)
      - World YWCA North American Regional Meeting, 1991 (Box 968, Folder 10)
    - Miscellaneous [most are not YWCA photographs]
      - General (Box 968, Folder 11)
      - Office machines (Box 968, Folder 12)
      - Women working (Box 968, Folder 13)
    - Unidentified, 1950s-90s
      - Events (Box 968, Folder 14)
      - Groups
        - Adults (Box 968, Folder 15-17)
        - Parents and children (Box 969, Folder 1)
      - Meetings (Box 969, Folder 2-5)
    - Individuals
      - Aaker-Adler (Box 970, Folder 1)
      - Ahlf-Alexander (Box 970, Folder 2)
      - Alexander, Alpha (Box 970, Folder 3)
      - Allan-Allyn (Box 970, Folder 4)
      - Always-Anderson (Box 970, Folder 5)
      - Anderson, Constance (Box 970, Folder 6)
      - Andrew- Arnold (Box 970, Folder 7)
      - Arrants-Aykroyd (Box 970, Folder 8)
      - Athannassiou, Athena (Box 970, Folder 9)
      - Babcock-Baker (Box 970, Folder 10)
      - Baker, Gwendolyn Calvert
        - Alone (Box 970, Folder 11)
        - Groups (Box 970, Folder 12)
      - Ball-Barger (Box 971, Folder 1)
      - Ball, Lucille (Box 971, Folder 2)
      - Barnes-Bayne (Box 971, Folder 3)
      - Barnes, Lilace (Box 971, Folder 4)
      - Beal-Begg (Box 971, Folder 5)
      - Belfield-Bertsch (Box 971, Folder 6)
      - Best-Birrell (Box 971, Folder 7)
      - Betzner, Era (Box 971, Folder 8)
      - Bishop-Bollard (Box 971, Folder 9)
      - Bondfield-Bowie (Box 971, Folder 10)
      - Bowles, Eva (Box 971, Folder 11)
      - Boyd-Boynton (Box 971, Folder 12)
      - Braden-Briganti (Box 972, Folder 1)
      - Briggs-Brock (Box 972, Folder 2)
      - Brooks-Brown (Box 972, Folder 3)
      - Brown, Dr. Anna L. (Box 972, Folder 4)
      - Bruce-Burner (Box 972, Folder 5)
      - Burnham-Byrd (Box 972, Folder 6)
      - Cabell-Calkins (Box 972, Folder 7)
      - Campbell-Carcaud (Box 972, Folder 8)
      - Carey-Carter (Box 972, Folder 9)
      - Cary-Cavert (Box 972, Folder 10)
      - Cedergren-Chambers (Box 972, Folder 11)
      - Chance-Chavez (Box 972, Folder 12)
      - Cheek-Christensen (Box 973, Folder 1)
      - Christie-Churchill (Box 973, Folder 2)
      - Clarenbach-Clarke (Box 973, Folder 3)
      - Clary-Cluett (Box 973, Folder 4)
      - Claytor, Helen Wilkins (Box 973, Folder 5)
      - Coan-Conde (Box 973, Folder 6)
      - Conkling-Copenhaver (Box 973, Folder 7)
      - Coppock, Grace (Box 973, Folder 8)
      - Corbett-Cotter (Box 973, Folder 9)
      - Courtney-Crawley (Box 973, Folder 10)
      - Cratty, Mabel
        - Alone (Box 973, Folder 11)
        - Groups (Box 973, Folder 12)
      - Creedy-Curtiss (Box 974, Folder 1)
      - Cushman, Vera Scott (Box 974, Folder 2)
      - Cuthbert-Cutler (Box 974, Folder 3)
      - Dabb-Davenport (Box 974, Folder 4)
      - Davids-Davis (Box 974, Folder 5)
      - Davison - Delahunt (Box 974, Folder 6)
      - Del Carmen - Derricotte (Box 974, Folder 7)
      - Derry-Dinsdale (Box 974, Folder 8)
      - Dixon-Dowling (Box 974, Folder 9)
      - Dodge, Grace Hoadley (Box 974, Folder 10)
      - Dodge Family (Box 974, Folder 11)
      - Dodge House, "Greystone" (Box 974, Folder 12)
      - Downey-Duthie (Box 974, Folder 13)
      - Earhart, Amelia (Box 975, Folder 1)
      - Earle-Ekim (Box 975, Folder 2)
      - Elliott, Grace Loucks (Box 975, Folder 3)
      - Ellis-Ervin (Box 975, Folder 4)
      - Eskew-Ewing (Box 975, Folder 5)
      - Faber-Farquar (Box 975, Folder 6)
      - Fasnacht-Figg (Box 975, Folder 7)
      - Fillingham-Fisher (Box 975, Folder 8)
      - Fitch-Ford (Box 975, Folder 9)
      - Forncrook-Franchino (Box 975, Folder 10)
      - Francis-Foxlee (Box 975, Folder 11)
      - French-Furness (Box 975, Folder 12)
      - French, Mary Billings (Mrs. John) (Box 975, Folder 13)
      - Gabehart-Gao (Box 976, Folder 1)
      - Garcia-Garrison (Box 976, Folder 2)
      - Garvin-Geissler (Box 976, Folder 3)
      - Genne, Elizabeth "Betty" (Box 976, Folder 4)
      - George-Gill (Box 976, Folder 5)
      - Glass-Gordon (Box 976, Folder 6)
      - Gorman-Graves (Box 976, Folder 7)
      - Graham, Jewel Freeman (Box 976, Folder 8)
      - Green-Guthrie (Box 976, Folder 9)
      - Haass-Hamilton (Box 976, Folder 10)
      - Hamlen-Hard (Box 976, Folder 11)
      - Hardin-Harm (Box 976, Folder 12)
      - Harris-Harrison (Box 977, Folder 1)
      - Harshaw-Haynes (Box 977, Folder 2)
      - Heap-Heineman (Box 977, Folder 3)
      - Height, Dorothy (Box 977, Folder 4-5)
      - Heiskell-Hewitt (Box 977, Folder 6)
      - Hickey-Hinckley (Box 977, Folder 7)
      - Hinton-Hoople (Box 977, Folder 8)
      - Hoover-Hoyt (Box 977, Folder 9)
      - Huang-Hynds (Box 977, Folder 10)
      - I (Box 977, Folder 11)
      - Jabif-Jewett (Box 978, Folder 1)
      - Jiagge-Jordan (Box 978, Folder 2)
      - Johns, R. Elizabeth (Box 978, Folder 3)
      - Kaiser-Kawai (Box 978, Folder 4)
      - Keane-Keyes (Box 978, Folder 5)
      - Khan-Khin Khin (Box 978, Folder 6)
      - Kiley-Kinnaird (Box 978, Folder 7)
      - Kistler-Kyte (Box 978, Folder 8)
      - Lacey-Landsrath (Box 978, Folder 9)
      - Lang-Layton (Box 978, Folder 10)
      - Leach-Lerner (Box 979, Folder 1)
      - Lerrigo, Edith (Box 979, Folder 2)
      - Leud-Lick (Box 979, Folder 3)
      - Lim-Livingston (Box 979, Folder 4)
      - Logan-Luce (Box 979, Folder 5)
      - Lucke-Lyons (Box 979, Folder 6)
      - Lyon, Sarah (Box 979, Folder 7)
      - MacArthur-Macy, [see also Mc] (Box 979, Folder 8)
      - Magee-Mapes (Box 979, Folder 9)
      - March-Marshall (Box 979, Folder 10)
      - Martin-Masuda (Box 979, Folder 11)
      - Marti, Beth (Box 979, Folder 12)
      - Mathai-Davis - Mayston (Box 979, Folder 13)
      - McAdam-McCutchen, [see also Mac] (Box 980, Folder 1)
      - McCulloch, Rhoda (Box 980, Folder 2)
      - McDonald-McKenna (Box 980, Folder 3)
      - McKenzie-Meares (Box 980, Folder 4)
      - Mei-Metzger (Box 980, Folder 5)
      - Michael-Miller (Box 980, Folder 6)
      - Milliken-Mitchell (Box 980, Folder 7)
      - Mo-Morgan (Box 980, Folder 8)
      - Moore, Elisabeth Luce (Box 980, Folder 9)
      - Morris-Morrow (Box 980, Folder 10)
      - Morton-Moyo (Box 980, Folder 11)
      - Mudge-Myers (Box 981, Folder 1)
      - Nakano-Newton (Box 981, Folder 2)
      - Nichol-Nizzardini (Box 981, Folder 3)
      - Niven, Charlotte (Box 981, Folder 4)
      - Noble-Nu (Box 981, Folder 5)
      - Oakes-Olive (Box 981, Folder 6)
      - Oliver-Owers (Box 981, Folder 7)
      - Pabst-Palmer (Box 981, Folder 8)
      - Paist, Theresa Wilbur (Box 981, Folder 9)
      - Papes-Parmour (Box 981, Folder 10)
      - Parolla-Peabody (Box 981, Folder 11)
      - Peacock-Penrose (Box 981, Folder 12)
      - Perkins-Persons (Box 981, Folder 13)
      - Peterson - Picton-Turbeville (Box 982, Folder 1)
      - Pierce-Porter (Box 982, Folder 2)
      - Post-Purkaple (Box 982, Folder 3)
      - Putnam, Glendora M (Box 982, Folder 4)
      - Q (Box 982, Folder 5)
      - Ra-Rawson (Box 982, Folder 6)
      - Read-Reynolds (Box 982, Folder 7)
      - Rhinehold-Riddick (Box 982, Folder 8)
      - Rice, Anna Virena (Box 982, Folder 9)
      - Ride-Rivera (Box 982, Folder 10)
      - Robarts-Robertson (Box 982, Folder 11)
      - Robey-Rockwell (Box 982, Folder 12)
      - Rockefeller, Mary French (Box 982, Folder 13)
      - Rodgers-Rohlf (Box 982, Folder 14)
      - Rohrwedder-Rossi (Box 983, Folder 1)
      - Roosevelt, Eleanor (Box 983, Folder 2)
      - Rouse-Royden (Box 983, Folder 3)
      - Rued-Rysdorp (Box 983, Folder 4)
      - Saar-San (Box 983, Folder 5)
      - Sanders-Sawyer (Box 983, Folder 6)
      - Schaedler-Schuessler (Box 983, Folder 7)
      - Scott-Selassi (Box 983, Folder 8)
      - Seldon-Shaw (Box 983, Folder 9)
      - Sheffield-Shuk (Box 983, Folder 10)
      - Sills-Simons (Box 983, Folder 11)
      - Sims-Slattery (Box 983, Folder 12)
      - Sleight-Southard (Box 983, Folder 13)
      - Spear-Spining (Box 983, Folder 14)
      - Speer, Emma Bailey (Box 983, Folder 15)
      - Stallard-Steinem (Box 984, Folder 1)
      - Steinbeck-Stoneking (Box 984, Folder 2)
      - Stratton-Strober (Box 984, Folder 3)
      - Suassuna-Syvertsen (Box 984, Folder 4)
      - Sweeney, Odile (Box 984, Folder 5)
      - Taka-Teixera (Box 984, Folder 6)
      - Terlin-Thoburn (Box 984, Folder 7)
      - Thomas-Thomson (Box 984, Folder 8)
      - Thoren-Titterington (Box 984, Folder 9)
      - Toomey-Tree (Box 984, Folder 10)
      - Trimble-Ultsch (Box 984, Folder 11)
      - Unzueta-Van Dusen (Box 984, Folder 12)
      - Van Derwerker-Vawter (Box 984, Folder 13)
      - Veech-Vivian (Box 985, Folder 1)
      - Vlastos-Vuilleumier (Box 985, Folder 2)
      - Wade-Walkinshaw (Box 985, Folder 3)
      - Walters-Watanabe (Box 985, Folder 4)
      - Watkins-Wellington (Box 985, Folder 5)
      - Wells-Weston (Box 985, Folder 6)
      - Whatmough-White (Box 985, Folder 7)
      - Whitford-Wildhager (Box 985, Folder 8)
      - Wilford-Williams (Box 985, Folder 9)
      - Williamson-Wiltz (Box 985, Folder 10)
      - Winant-Withers (Box 985, Folder 11)
      - Wohrle-Worrell (Box 986, Folder 1)
      - Wright-Wyman (Box 986, Folder 2)
      - Wright, Sara-Alyce (Box 986, Folder 3)
      - X-Z (Box 986, Folder 4)
      - Unidentified (Box 986, Folder 5-7)
  - Subseries B. National Board and National Administrative Office
    - National Board
      - Meetings, 1970, 1987 (Box 987, Folder 1-4)
      - Portraits: contact sheets and negatives, circa 1990s (Box 987, Folder 5)
      - Soviet Women's Committee, 1987 (Box 987, Folder 6)
    - National Board and Staff
      - Groups, general, circa 1910-98, n.d. (Box 987, Folder 7-11)
      - Project Redesign meeting, 4 Feb 1992 (Box 987, Folder 12)
      - Staff parties
        - General, 1975-94 (Box 987, Folder 13)
        - Final party at 600 Lexington Ave., 12 May 1982 (Box 987, Folder 14)
        - Sara-Alyce Wright retirement, Jan 1984 (Box 987, Folder 15)
        - Gwen Baker retirement, n.d. (Box 987, Folder 16)
    - Buildings and Properties
      - Miscellaneous and Altamont, Millbrook, New York (Box 988, Folder 1)
      - Asilomar Conference Grounds, Pacific Grove, California
        - General (Box 988, Folder 2)
        - Administration Building (Box 988, Folder 3)
        - Class Hall and Chapel (Box 988, Folder 4)
        - Crocker Dining Room (Box 988, Folder 5)
        - Health Cottage and Hilltop Cottage (Box 988, Folder 6)
        - Long Houses (Box 988, Folder 7)
        - Beach Houses (Box 988, Folder 8)
        - Merrill Hall and Scripps Reserve Cottage (Box 988, Folder 9)
        - Tent Houses (Box 988, Folder 10)
        - Maps (Box 988, Folder 11)
      - Fletcher Farm, Ludlow, Vermont
        - General (Box 988, Folder 12)
        - Photo album (Box 988, Folder 13)